Weijia Lu is a researcher with two PhDs & Sr. Manager of an innoventional team of diverse technical directions: has over 10 years of experiences in data modeling. artificial intelligence application, multiphysics numerical analysis, signal processing, computer visualization and likely; has demonstrated excellence in academic research.



CONTACT

AlfredWJLu@gmail.com

+86 137 7436 3137

Shanghai, CN

Personal Homesite

in Professional Portal

0000-0002-7899-6034

SKILLS

Industry

Healthcare **Automobile**



Leadership & Management

Strategic Planning Quality Assurance Team Leadership Visionary Thinking



Research & Delivery

Signal Processing (e.g. Image, Medical Signal, Text ...)

Deep/Machine Learning

(e.g. GAN, RL ...)

Compute Architecture (e.g. Model Pruning, FL ...)

Physics (e.g. FIELD II, Abersim, COMSOL ...)

Software Implementation 0000 (e.g. Python, C/C++, R, Matlab, GNU Tools,

Linux, Docker, HTML, PHP, DevOps ...) Hardware Design & MCUs

(e.g. ATmega128, MSP430, 80C51, TDA4)

Languages

Mandarin **English**



CERTIFICATES

- + JHU certified Data Science Specialization
- + Bk certified Big Data Analysis with Spark
- + GE certified Green Belt of Lean Six Sigma
- + CN Automation certified Mid-Class Eng

WORK HISTORY

Chief Al Scientist & Sr. Mgr **Q** UAES, Shanghai, CN

UAES is No 1. in Driving Technology in China. Its product enclosed EMS, BMS, VCU, VCP, eAxials, TMS so on so forth.

1 09/2018 - 08/2019

Senior Researcher **♀** Tencent AI Lab, Shenzhen, CN

Lead research on deep learning algorithm for medical pathological diagnosis; 2 SCIE papers, 1 top-rank conference

1 04/2017 - 09/2018

9 GE Digital, Shanghai, CN

Staff Data Scientist

Lead research on deep learning algorithm for auto-annotation on physiological signal, predictive maintenance for large healthcare equipment; deliver web platform for radiomics study in hospital; 1 top-rank conference, 1 US patent

1 05/2012 - 04/2017

Lead Engineer Q GE Global Research, Shanghai, CN

Lead research on offshore drilling ultrasonic velocimetry, lift solution optimization for well lifecycle management, detection algorithm & physical modeling for micro-calcifications twinkling study, $automation \ tool \ for \ GE \ controllers; \ 1 \ SCIE \ paper, \ 1 \ top-rank \ conference, \ 1 \ CTO \ award, \ 3 \ US \ patents$

1 09/2010 - 05/2012

Scientist Philips Research, Shanghai, CN

Research on signal processing algorithm for ultrasound blood velocimetry, and denoising algorithm for motion artifacts on ECG signal; 2 US patents

EDUCATION

6 05/2008 - 09/2011

University of Aizu,

PhD of Computer Science

Aizu-Wakamatsu City, JP

Research on computational model & 3D visualization for cardiac electrophysiological study; 1 SCIE paper, 2 conferences

1 09/2004 - 06/2009

♀ Fudan University, Shanghai, CN

PhD of Electronic Engineering

Research on epi-cardial mapping system, including its data acquisition hardware, firmware, USB driver, 3D interpolation algorithm; 1 SCIE paper, 1 Chinese top-rank journal paper, 3 conferences

6 09/1999 - 07/2003

Nanjing University of Sc. and Tec., Naniing, CN

BSc of Electronic Engineering

Major in radar system and signal processing

ACHIEVEMENTS, HONOURS AND AWARDS

- TCTO Physical & Digital Integration Award, GE, 2016
- Best Employee, UAES, 2020
- ¶ 1st prize of CMQMA Excellent Quality Management, CN, 2022
- Pearl Engineer, Pudong Shanghai, 2024

RECOMMENDATIONS

"...Weijia has developed an excellent reputation within our organization as a dedicated, insightful and easy to work with colleague..." - by Chief Engineer @ GE Ultrasound Probes

PUBLICATIONS

Design and Implementation of a New System for Whole-Atrial Epicardial Mapping Cuiwei Yang, Weijia Lu, Xiaomei Wu, and Zuxiang Fang International Journal of Bioelectromagnetism About: Design an electronic system to records electrophysiology activity of heart.	æ	Link
A New Scheme for Observation and Interpretation Atrial Fibrillation * Weijia Lu, Zuxiang Fang * 2008 in Proceedings of the 2nd International Conference on Bioinformatics and Biomedical Engineering	æ	Link
A Visual Expression to Show Epicardial Electrical Activity Comprehensively Tou Zhou, Weijia Lu, Cuiwei Yang, and Zuxiang Fang in Proceedings of the 2nd International Conference on Bioinformatics and Biomedical Engineering	æ	Link
Dynamic Epicardial Mapping Using 3D Emulation * Weijia Lu, Tuo Zhou, Cuiwei Yang, and Zuxiang Fang 2008 in Proceedings of the International Conference on Biomedical Engineering and Informatics	G,	Link
Development of Epicardial Mapping System for Study Atrial Fibrillation Cuiwei Yang, Weijia Lu, Tuo Zhou, Xiaomei Wu, and Zuxiang Fang in Proceedings of the International Conference on Biomedical Engineering and Informatics	Q,	Link
A Method for Real-time Sampling and Smoothly Scrolling in Epicardial Mapping System Weijia Lu, Cuiwei Yang, and Zuxiang Fang Dournal of Biomedical Engineering (Chinese), vol.26, pp.1102-1105 About: Software design of employing DirectX to smoothly scrolling multiple signals on screen in a high speed sampling scenario. The corresponding GUI of in IJB2007.		Link tem reported
A Parallel Algorithm for Computer Simulation of Electrocardiogram Based on MPI Wenfeng Shen, Weijia Lu, Daming Wei, Weimin Xu, Xin Zhu, and Shizhong Yuan 2009 in Proceedings of 8th IEEE/ACIS International Conference on Computer and Information Science About: Software design of ECG computational simulation in HPC. A HPC version of Wei-Harumi Model.	œ	Link
Implementation of a Novel Interpolating Method to Epicardial Potential Mapping for Atrial Fibrillation Study * Weijia Lu, Cuiwei Yang, Zuxiang Fang, Xingpeng Liu, Xin Zhu, and Daming Wei 2010	oatia	
A Computer Model Based on Real Anatomy for Electrophysiology Study ** Weijia Lu, Daming Wei, Xin Zhu, and Wenxi Chen ** 2011		Link eal anatomy,
Method and Device for Detecting Occlusion/Reopening of an Artery and System for Measuring Systolic Blood Pressure Yinan Chen, Weijia Lu, Jianyi Zhong, Ajay Anand, John Petruzzello US 20140180114 A1 About: Method to detecting blood pressure using pulse wave ultrasound. First achievement during my career path fulfilled in Philips Research. Computer Simulation of Cathode Ablation for Atrial Fibrillation	æ	Link
 ★ Xin Zhu, Di Yang, Weijia Lu, Wenxi Chen, Daming Wei, Koji Fukuda, and Hiroaki Shimokawa 2014	æ	Link
Method to Develop Coded Excitation for Velocimetry in Downhole Drilling * Weijia Lu, Ran Niu, Longtao Yuan, Xin Qu, Heng Wu, Jing Ye 2015 in Proceedings of 15th IEEE International Conference on Computer and Information Technology About: Encoding/decoding algorithm for pulse wave ultrasound, which can significantly improving spatial resolution without jeopardizing signal penetro of my studying related to B-Flow and designed for early kick detection project, and my first publication in GE Research.		Link 1. By-product

Dominant Factor Analysis of B-flow Twinkling Sign with Phantom and Simulation Data

Weijia Lu, Bruno Haider

About: A mechanistic study of twinkly phenomenon showup in B-Flow ultrasonic imaging. A study established a multiphysics computational model to de tic coupling of ultrasonic field and solid granules, then designed phantom study to validate the mechanistic theory. The agreement of simulation and found by a post-processing algorithm in also reported in this study. The break-through achievement is acknowledged by the chief engineer of medical under the control of the chief engineer of medical under the control of the chief engineer of medical under the chief engineer	scrib phan	tom study is
Sensing Systems and Methods for Detecting Changes in Downhole Hydrocarbon and Gas Species Weijia Lu, Yi Liao		
 2017	æ	Link
Method to Annotate Arrhythmias by Deep Network		
 Weijia Lu, Jie Shuai, Shuyan Gu, Joel Xue ≅ 2018		Link ling collabo-
New Boundary Constraint Loss to Facilitate Glands Segmentation		
Weijia Lu, Jianhua Yao, Xiao Han, Haocheng Shen	_	
2019 Journal of Medical Imaging and Medical Informatics About: Segmentation of glands on pathological image, learning method by a new loss function. My first publication of using AI on medical image and final Italy. AI Lab.		Link d in Tencent
An Attentive Pruning Method for Edge Computing		
Yang Gao, Hao Gong, Weijia Lu , Chen Su, Zhang Ni and Qinghua Wang	Q.	Challe Challe
2019 in Proceedings of 20th International Conference on Machine Learning and Computing About: Method to prune object detection network, first publication of UAES AI Lab after my enrollment of UAES as chief AI scientist.	70	Link
System and Method for Identifying Cardiac Arrhythmias With Deep Neural Networks		
 Weijia Lu, Shuyan Gu, Joel Xue, Jie Shuai, Hu Lifei 2020 ■ US20200178825 	Q,	Link
2020 US20200178825 About: The corresponding patent of publication CIT2018, authored by Joel, the principle engineer of GE Diagnostic Cardiology.	•	LITIK
Microsatellite Instability Prediction of Uterine Corpus Endometrial Carcinoma Based on HE Histology Whole-Slide Imagin	ıg	
Tongxin Wang, Weijia Lu, Fan Yang, Li Liu, Zhong-Yi Dong, Weimin Tang, Jia Chang, Wenjing Huan, Kun Huang and Jianhua Yao		
2020 In Proceedings of IEEE 17th International Symposium on Biomedical Imaging, ISBI About: An new Al paradigm to predict MSI on pathological image. A multi-instance learning method by me and Tongxin, when he was working as an in Lab.	-	Link n Tencent Al
Development and interpretation of a pathomics-based model for the prediction of microsatellite instability in Colorectal	Can	cer
Cao Rui, Fan Yang, Si-Cong Ma, Li Liu, Yu Zhao, Yan Li, Dehua Wu, Tongxin Wang, Weijia Lu , Wei-Jing Cai, Hong-bo Zhu, Xue-Jun Guo, Yuwen Lu, Jun-ji Huan, Wei-min, Tang, Kun Huang, Junzhou Huang, Jianhua Yao and Zhong-Yi Dong	e Kua	ng, Wenjing
2020 Theranostics About: A collaboration research fulfilled by Tencent AI Lab and Nanfang hospital, and a systematic description of methodology reported in ISBI2020.	æ	Link
Processing Methods, Devices, Equipment and Storage Media for Vehicle Data		
Peng Liu, Weijia Lu, Bingyang Li, Hao Gong, Jie Zhuang and Tao Song	^	
2020 © CN202011480936.0 About: Optimization of sampling point selection for utilizing gaussian process regression in torque prediction. Comparing with ASCMO modeling method use only 70% of sampling point without any decresing in prediction performance.		Link ETAS Bosch,
Construction Method, Device and Storage Medium for Engine Exhaust System Temperature Model		
Bingyang Li, Hao Gong, Weijia Lu , Peng Liu, Chunshan Ma, Yang Wang, Jianqiang Wang and Zhiwei Wang	^	
2021 © CN202110499356.4 About: A swarm intelligence method to optimize super-parameter map of the control algorithm.	*6	Link
Dual Batch Size Training: An efficient MGD adaptive batch size method		
Yuhang Du, Wenfeng Shen, Baohua Liu, Weijia Lu and Hao Gong	0	
2021 in Proceedings of 2021 IEEE 33rd International Conference on Tools with Artificial Intelligence, ICTAI	70	Link
Method, Device and Storage Medium of PCB Welding Defect Detection Weijia Lu, Peng Liu, Bingyang Li, Chuang Liu, Wei Shen, Huan Ge, Yu Jing, Jie Zhang, Qi Wang and Yu Cao		
a weijia tu , Peng Liu, Bingyang Li, Chuang Liu, Wei Sheri, Huan Ge, Yu Jing, Jie Zhang, Qi Wang and Yu Cao a 2021	90	Link
About: A two-stage method to predict welding defect areas and defect type based on selective welding image.	•	
Method, Device and Storage Medium of Image Recognition for Chip Welding Defect		
Peng Liu, Weijia Lu, Bingyang Li, Chuang Liu, Tong Ma and Fayu Qian	G	Limb.
2021 © CN202110992821.8 About: Welding defect detection based on resistance welding image.	ъ	Link

Yi Cui, Wenfeng Shen, Jian Zhang, Weijia Lu , Chuang Liu, Lingge Sun and Sisi Chen 2022 in Proceedings of 2022 International Joint Conference on Neural Networks, IJCNN About: A generative adversarial network to detect intrusion on vehicle gateway.	æ	Link		
Knock detection method and device for PCSP ignition strategy Xiaofeng Ma, Weijia Lu, Gang Xi and Jianqiang Wang CN 114781425 A About: A new knock detection method when traditional algorithm failed on PCSP ignition strategy. This method deal with labeling noise by cross train designed hand-crafted features.		Link and c		
Gradient-Based Meta-Learning Using Uncertainty to Weigh Loss for Few-Shot Learning Lin Ding, Wenfeng Shen, Weijia Lu, Peng Liu and Shengbo Chen Loss of ICCECE In Proceedings of ICCECE	Q	Link		
Towards Designing an Attentive Deep Trajectory Predictor Based on Bluetooth Low Energy Signal Weijia Lu, Xiaofeng Ma, Xiaodong Zhang, Zhifei Yang and Qinghua Wang Din Proceedings of 57th Annual Conference on Information Sciences and Systems, CISS About: A small but carefully designed MOE network to predict cellphone location in a key-less entry scenario. The deep learning network, with only 700 ters, has been deployed in a ECU with 300MHz frequency and limited code segment. This network has two branches, one to predict the angle and anoth distance, and whole network is sparse activated. Moreover a carefully designed loss function is reported in this study to accelerate network training.	float	•	arame-	
Distributed Training Methods and Systems for Models Weijia Lu, Xiaodong Zhang, Zhifei Yang, Xiaofeng Ma, Chuang Liu and Wangchen Lin CN 116822619 A	æ	Link		
A Method for Automatic Capacity Allocation Shuyu Jiang, Weijia Lu, Na Li, Huan Ge and Bingyang Li CN 116384669 A About: Automatic production line allocation using linear programming and cbc solver.	⊗	Link		
A Power Battery Balancing Controller, Balancing Control Method, and Electric Vehicle Chuang Liu, Xichun Ke, Zhifei Yang, Weijia Lu, Xiaodong Zhang and Xiang Di CN 116674432 A About: A heuristic strategy for battery balancing. In nowadays, heterogenization of power battery cells becomes a critical factor of e-car lifespan. Certa provided to automatically initiate balancing process and ultimately ameliorate the heterogenization. But the chip will shutdown balancing once the tempa pre-set threshold. So this patent introduce a method to fulfilled balancing process without trigger the temperature protection strategy.	ain cl		as been	
A Reinforcement Learning-based Battery Balancing Method and Device Zhifei Yang, Xichun Ke, Chuang Liu, Weijia Lu, Xiaodong Zhang and Xiang Di CN 116767024 A About: The reinformant learning verion of CN 116674432 A. Moreover this patent reports the method to establish the digital twin model of the balancing digital model is used as the environment during policy training.		Link rdwa		
A Curve Information Processing Method, Device, Storage Medium, and Detection Equipment Peng Liu, Lin Sun, Weijia Lu and Tong Ma CN 115631139 A	æ	Link		
A Target Detection Method, Device, Storage Medium, Sensor, and Controller Peng Liu, Weijia Lu, Lin Sun, Can Zhang and Tong Ma CN 116452916 A About: Contrastive learning method for target detection.	œ.	Link		
A Target Detection Method, Machine Vision Device, Storage Medium, and Controller Peng Liu, Lin Sun, Weijia Lu, Jie Zhang, Wei Shen, Yu Jin and Huan Ge CN 117726855 A About: Semi-Supervised learning method for target detection.	æ	Link		
A Product Testing Method, Data Management Method, Apparatus, Medium and Controller Weijia Lu, Xiaodong Zhang, Can Zhang, Zhifei Yang, Xiaofeng Ma, Chuang Liu, Bingyang Li, Feng Wu, Xuzhou Zhang, Jing Ye, Yongyi Liu, Xichun Ke, Jianfei Zheng, Jie Bai and Chen Sheng				
2024 © CN 118860853 A About: A test case generation tool utilizing signal matrix, IO configuration and large language model.	æ	Link		
A Method for Model Data Processing, a Simulation Apparatus, a Storage Medium, and a Testing System. Zhifei Yang, Xiaofeng Ma, Weijia Lu, Xiaodong Zhang, Wangchen Lin, Ting Li, Fei Sun, Qiang Fang and Gang Xi CN 118732531 A About: A method to establish digital twin model based on a new neural ODE structure.	⊗	Link		

Liang Tao, Yangguang Cui, Xiaodong Zhang, Wenfeng Shen, Weijia Lu

2024	Part D: Journal of Automobile Engineering	% Link
About: A vehicle	trajectory model, federated learned from real vehicle data, with multi-head design and federated clustering.	The corresponding method is protected in
natent CN 11682	2619 Δ	

A Comfortable and Robust DRL-based Car-following Policy Incorporating Lateral Information under Cut-in Scenarios

👺 Yifei Shen, Zhifei Yang, **Weijia Lu**, Wenfeng Shen, Zhou Lei

🗎 2024 🗐 in Proceedings of 35th IEEE Intelligent Vehicles Symposium, IV

% Link

About: A reinforcement learning policy to significant increase the safety. The vehicle trajectory model, federated learned from real vehicle data and reported in PartD 2024, provide critical lateral information.

Improving Generalization and Personalization in Long-Tailed Federated Learning via Classifier Retraining

Yuhang Li, Liu Tong, Wenfeng Shen, Yangguang Cui, Weijia Lu

🗎 2024 **I** in Proceedings of 30th International European Conference on Parallel and Distributed Computing, Euro-par About: A resampling strategy to address heterogenization issue of data distribution in a federated learning.

% Link